A Guide to the Guy Davenport Letters, 1974-1985
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Guy Davenport Letters 1974-1985
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10539-p
This collection contains eleven items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from George Minkoff, Alford, Mass., on December 9, 1991.
Scope and Content
In this collection Guy Davenport, an American author, discusses his current work, reviewing and reviews by Klinkowitz and others, Klinkowitz's inclusion of him in Contemporary novelists, and various authors and their writing styles.
Contents List
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Rapids, Iowa July 1, 1974, TLS, 1 p., w/ env
  Refers to his book Tatlin! and a review by JK.
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa July 14, 1974, TLS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Thanks him for 'The Vonnegut Statement,' and mentioning the work of Paul Metcalf.
- Letter from Guy Davenport, in South Carolina, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa August 19, 1974, ALS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Mentions reviews of his book [ Tatlin! ] and being "down in the late Confederacy, trying to get some writing done."
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa July 23, 1979, TLS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Discusses the nature of reviewing works and [Roy R.] Behrens' acquaintance.
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa February 27, 1981, TLS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Refers to his books about to be published, including The Geography of the Imagination, Eclogues, Trois Caprices, and The Mimes of Herondas; praises JK's ability to critique; indicates that he would rather be painting; mentions an experimental work of his, The Robert Browning Overture; and, mentions Roy [R. Behren] and his book.
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa March 5, 1981, TLS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Discusses various authors, his perception of "comparative realism," his views on technology and John Updike and his writing; and, thanks JK for sharing one of his books.
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa October 5, 1982, TPCS
  Refers to "particulars from Roy" and the Contemporary Novelists
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa October 13, 1982, TNS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Thanks him for the pages from Contemporary Novelists, which included GD.
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa January 4, 1985, TLS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Mentions the publication of [ The Geography of the Imagination ] and comments on Jerzy Kosinski and Steve Dixon and their writing styles.
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa January 15, 1985, TNS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Concerns Brad Morrow or Joan Crane doing a book on his "ravings" for JK's series, and mentions correpondence with [Marc] Chenetier
- Letter from Guy Davenport, Lexington, Kentucky, to Jerome Klinkowitz, Cedar Falls, Iowa January 27, 1985, TLS, 1 p., w/ env.
  Reads JK's adventures with Jerzy Kosinski and comments favorably on the volumes.